for everybody. We will be recording and
letting everybody in from the lobby.
That usually takes a minute or so. And
so in the meanwhile, while everyone is
still coming in from the lobby, uh just
as a reminder to everybody, we do record
these meetings. It is recording
currently and so please make sure that
language is appropriate. Um, I'm Dominic
Zerllo and I am the director for the
center for medical cannabis and
psilocybin and this is the training and
education committee uh for the medical
psilocybin advisory board with Brenda
Bergard as chair. And with that, Brenda,
I will turn it over to you.
>> All right. Well, thank you everyone for
coming today. Uh, we have uh a little
bit of a an agenda up here. Uh so uh
Jorge could you uh go ahead and um pull
it up and see if we can get that
together.
>> I am I am downloading that as we speak.
>> Okay.
>> In the meantime, Brenda, do you want to
do introductions?
>> Oh yes, thank you. Thank you for
reminding me. I am Brenda Burgar the for
training chairing uh the training and
education uh here and uh let's see who
do we have can you raise your hand and
present yourself if you are on the board
okay uh Kate Hawk you would uh like to
present yourself.
>> Okay. It doesn't seem to be
>> Oh, there we go.
>> Okay, there we are.
>> Okay, cool. Yeah, Kate, you can talk
when you're ready.
>> Yeah. Hi there. Thanks for undisabling
my mic. I'm I'm Kate Hawk. I'm not on
any board, but I am a participating part
of this uh training and education
committee and um in Santa Fe. Just happy
to be here today and pitch in as I can.
Thank you.
>> Thank you, Kate. And I want to add that
we are forming a little um uh uh not a
committee, but we're forming a group for
um helping out with the training and
education because there's so many
working parts to this. They're part of
the the team that is helping me uh pull
all of this information together and to
present it to the public uh for comment
and uh input. So uh
>> let's see next. Who's next? We have Dr.
Larry.
>> Larry.
>> Hi everybody. Larry Leman, um member of
the advisory board, chair of the end of
life committee and very interested in uh
in training issues. So nice to be here.
>> Thank you, Larry.
>> Brenda, we have a couple of
introductions in the chat that I can
read. Uh let's see. We have we have
Chris Pascus uh from the advisory board,
Advocate and Veterans.
Thanks, Larry. I mean, thanks, Chris.
Thanks for [laughter]
all. And then we have Don Moser.
>> One of those days today.
>> Yeah, totally. And then we have Don
Moser from Las Vegas, New Mexico. Glad
to be here.
>> Thank you, Don.
>> Those are the only hands I see at the
moment.
>> Okay, so let's go ahead and roll out um
the agenda. Anyone else here? Okay, I
see um uh uh Anifea uh she's uh um on
the alliance uh the PM MHA Alliance uh
Dr. Lita Fatimi uh founder of conscious
uh physicians and psychedelics academy
and Ellen Shimls uh she says hello
everyone Ellen Shimls psychiatric mental
health nurse practitioner army veteran
and clinical professor at Emory
University living in Albuquerque New
Mexico educator and advocate. Uh we have
Gregory Evans from the committee and
he's present. Um let's see get some I'll
just rattle it off here. We have Ann
Mitts uh uh clinical facilitator
Colorado house um uh residence and
director of fluence training pro program
in Colorado and she will also be
presenting today. Thank you Ann. Uh
let's see anyone else coming into the
fold here for this meeting.
just wait another minute or so.
Okay. So, let's go ahead and um start
with the agenda today. Okay. If we could
pull down so we can get the agenda here.
Oh, here's Ian. Ian is here. Uh uh Ian
Dunn who's also on the board. Um, he's
joining us today.
>> Brenda, I have the agenda pulled up for
you.
>> Okay. I'm not seeing the whole thing
here. Can you just scroll
>> to the top of the page here?
>> There we are. Sorry about that.
>> Okay.
>> Um, all righty. Thank you. Uh so on
today's agenda we have uh for training
and education agenda we have Ann Mets uh
who's going to be uh presenting
um her education and training on here
today. Um, a couple of things that we're
doing here is, um, we're going to focus
a little bit more on the practicum and
didactic hour requirements
for reciprocity in the full program. Um,
and so we need some more um consensus on
that today. uh for example, reciprocity
needs fewer didactic requirements and a
20hour practicum full program with more
didactic requirements and equal or more
practicum. So initially what we're we're
we're
thinking about here is um 50 didactic
hours core curriculum or uh state
modules um 40 practicum hours um uh we
were also thinking maybe 50/50 on this
one too. um a few of us uh in um the
other uh team that I have for the
education and training we're are kind of
really kind of almost there with with
the hours but we're we're deciding that
this looks the the the best right now um
and that is with um experiential with
the medicine practicing with other
professionals similar to the Colorado
requirements
um 80 uh supervised practice hours and
and I don't want to I know a lot of
people get mixed up with what supervised
hours look like. For clinicians, we when
we say supervised hours, that usually
means someone who's um
trained in supervision, but this is got
a different um uh definition to it. But
it's usually the supervision is um
practice hours is someone there that has
already gone through all of the
education and training. Um you know,
imagine being in a clinic and having
like a director uh above you watching um
or making sure that you're uh doing your
due diligence in uh the practicum hours.
So working with clients under
supervision. Uh this c currently does
not uh exist in other states and instead
um uh we require more didactic hours in
in um in this um adding this portion
provides a deeper and more robust
learning experience
because um it's it's more of being there
and working with the patient or the the
client. uh that is the most vital part
and and holding space for for
uh what is going on in the actual um
uh treatment of what someone is going
through their experience. Um and so um I
have a couple other things going on here
for the agenda. Um suggestion is uh uh
using existing programs and modules from
existing education programs kind of like
a cherry-picking thing to modify it for
New Mexico to save time, reduce
redundancy and any um you know edit any
uh in applicable information that is not
part of the New Mexico module at
competencies. So, in other words, like
if there's other things in modules from
other education
um places that don't really apply to New
Mexico, but maybe there's some things
that we can. So it it's really looking
at other programs very closely and uh
taking what they have so we're not
reinventing the wheel and and um trying
to
um make it uh almost overload in the
information
uh core competencies adding and
addressing any needs in the core
competencies if uh you know looking over
that I think we've pretty much gone over
the core competencies
uh that will satisfy the DO. Um if the
DO has any other uh addressing needs
about that uh you know during these
meetings it would be good for um us to
hear from uh uh the department. Um I
would like to see a modular on dosing. I
don't know if we're there yet or not.
I've only been able to go to some of
these meetings. But um I think that is
one of the points that um uh I I think
we're we're missing in that education
part. Um study materials for classes,
literature, data journals, online
learning and testing programs, etc.,
etc. You know, what are the costs there?
I don't know if we're there yet, but
maybe we could have a discussion about
it. And of course, reciprocity. Uh when
will the New Mexico modules be available
for reciprocity?
uh addressing the other specialties, end
of life care, uh addiction, cere
ceremonial native practices, pastoral
and spiritual u medical specialties
including people who um are uh
specializing especially in pain and an
adjunct to their uh professions. So in
the end of life meeting um it was uh
presented as an adjunct to their
profession. So part of their learning,
right, Larry? It was part of their um
additional learning.
>> Um
can you hear me? Can I
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. Um there actually wasn't a
decision on that. There was um people
who felt that the the recommendation was
for 15 to 20 hours. There's people who
felt that that should be part of all of
the programs. Other people felt that
that could possibly be an add-on. So
that was still um uh still under
discussion and I think the idea is to
try to you know see how this committee
is looking at this and see how that
would would work. Um certainly um well
you know if you're going to have 15
hours of end of life you're not going to
have 50 hours total. So I mean you have
to kind of look at how that would play
out with uh with other recommendations
and considerations.
>> Oh yes. I think um you know how um the
education and training is going to align
themselves with other committees too. So
that's another big piece of the puzzle
that we all have to kind of come
together and kind of sync up with each
other in that uh regard. Um, for right
now, uh, I just want to see if, um, I
want everyone to hold their questions
and comments, uh, for after, uh, the
presentation with, uh, an if, if that's,
uh, at all possible. Yes, Larry.
>> No, I'm good.
>> Okay. All right. So, um,
uh, I think this would be, um, a good
time. Uh so I want to just make sure if
Ann are you ready to present?
>> Yes, absolutely. Um I'm happy to hear
>> I hope that's okay. I just unmuted
myself. Um and Jorge has the PowerPoint
that I was going to use.
>> I sure do. And then yeah, that's quite
right. You you are you are in presenter
mode. So feel free to speak and I will
pull in your document just right now if
you give me one second.
There you are. How's that for you?
>> Uh [laughter]
as long as you all can see. I can't see
anything, but we're going to just be
cool with that. There we go.
>> Brenda. Brenda, you can see this docu
the PowerPoint.
>> Uh, yes, I can see it. Thank you.
>> Great. Um, well, I'll just let you know
when I want to switch. Um, just good
afternoon everyone. Thank you so much
for this opportunity to talk to you
today. Um, a brief word on where I'm
coming from here. So, I've worked on
fluent training programs, both Oregon
and Colorado accredited programs. So,
I've seen firsthand how state models
translate into classrooms, practicum
sites, and graduates. Uh, I've completed
the MAPS um MDMA training program, which
is another gold standard in psych
psychedelic education. And I've also
consulted with people who helped design
that curriculum. I've consulted on the
national certification standards for
psychedelic education that was proposed
through the National Psychedelic
Association. I have no conflicts of
interest here in New Mexico. I have no
stake in any training program, healing
center, or applicant. And really what I
think I bring uh to this conversation is
a network. People who have already run
into these questions in Oregon and in
Colorado. And what I'm going to present
today, I would say, are general
recommendations. It's not really a
finalized plan. So, I hope what I have
to say sparks discussion and refinement.
Um the recommendations that I've made
draw on four sources. Uh the first would
be this committee's June 12th and June
25th drafts. The healing advocacy funds
qualitative analysis of Colorado's
training requirements which were um it
was a interviews with 24 program
operators, graduates, indigenous
scholars, and legacy practitioners and a
comparison of Oregon's 120 and
Colorado's 150 hours of training. And I
also consulted with a number of
experienced colleagues including Memoru
um which is a healing center that has a
consultation model out of Boulder that
um I I really like and think could be
valuable. So I think the frame
throughout all of this is really
calibration. We want this program to be
rigorous enough where it's defensible
for the public and the legislature, but
it's also lean enough so that the
training stays accessible. And with that
in mind, we really have to be
intentional about every hour that we we
require because cost to trainees is
real. For a licensed clinician, 120 hour
practicum isn't just unpaid time. Every
practicum hour is a foregone client
hour. And at typical clinical rates,
120hour practicum is roughly $18,000 to
$24,000 in loss revenue. And that's
before tuition, supervision fees, and
any travel. And that burden lands
exactly on the clinicians that we want
most in this program. And eventually it
lands on the patients. So next slide.
Great.
>> And I'm on slide three with the 84
dactic hours. Does that work?
>> Could you go to slide two actually?
>> Yes. Yes. I was just there. Okay.
>> Sorry. Sorry. Sorry. Sorry. Sorry.
>> Four recommendations here. um each with
its own slide. Uh my first
recommendation really is a logistical
one. I really think it would be
meaningful and important to retitle
practitioner as licensed provider.
Practitioner tells a patient nothing
about training and it also collides with
nurse practitioner. Um I think that
licensed provider really names the
qualification itself. Second is a single
84hour didactic standard. Third is a
scaffolded pract practicum with a
training permit. Both of these reduce
hours relative to the cl um to the
current draft. And I'll make that
argument directly. Structure and
checkpoints um I think ultimately
protect the public better than raw hour
counts. Um and of course every hour
that's added is a cost that's passed on
to trainees and to the patients. And
then fourthly, tie consultation signoff
to having presented two cases. This is I
think what makes the reduction in
practicum hours defensible. Someone
experienced evaluates the new permites
own casework before they're able to
practice fully independently.
And now we can go to slide three.
So didactic hours.
I think 84 hours really sits in the
defensible middle. um Oregon requires
120 and yet or uh graduates in the
Colorado analysis consistently said that
the didactic portion still really lacked
depth on anyone's skill. Um so what we
can conclude really from that is that
more hours did not necessarily buy
depth. Um Colorado's 150 hours raises
cost and access concerns and I think it
really risks pushing people outside of
the regulated model. um and it necess
isn't clearly supported by outcome data.
Uh so just the allocation broadly for
the 84 hours um we would want to look at
um 25 to 30 hours of core psychotherapy
skills and ethics. This is really
consistent with the Colorado
recommendation that ethics be about 20%
of didactic time. Module on end of life
care that's about 10 to 15 hours. Trauma
eight hours, medicine dosing and
research literacy about eight hours. The
New Mexico module six to eight,
treatment modules um six to eight as
well. Screening, suicidality and crisis
response would be about 5 to 8 hours.
Sematic awareness and touch uh would be
around four to six. And then history,
historical and traditional use would be
about 3 to four hours. Um something
that's new that's in um this
recommendation that's not in other
programs would be to focus on
challenging experiences including
conditions like HPPPD. So thinking 2 to
four hours. Um and I think these ranges
are really illustrative. Um but we what
we want really is the binding minimum of
about 84 hours. Um one kind of point I
wanted to make about the trauma hours.
Uh 8 hours is not PTSD treatment
training. Um that obviously is a much
longer and extensive process. Um but it
really would cover recognizing
dissociation and trauma responses,
sematic work, and how to deescalate. Um
I think that wherever PTSD treatment
would sit outside of a licensed provider
scope, I think it's going to be
important to have collaboration with a
PTSD trained provider um as required or
requested. You'll notice that there are
no tiers by professional background. Um,
you know, I wanted to in include the J
June 25th draft module by module test
out excluding of course the New Mexico
module. So, this lets experienced
clinicians move more efficiently without
actually lowering the single quality
bar.
Um, I'm happy to move on to the next
one.
Uh, I just think something else would
imagine when we're talking about the
dactic is that basically all of the
Colorado interviewees said that they
wanted um the didactic to be more
applied and have opportunities to
practice rather than just provide
PowerPoint presentations and lectures.
So I think that's really going to be
something that um should be integrated
and as we're evaluating programs is how
much like practice are people having or
is this just you know listening to
PowerPoint presentations like you're all
so patiently doing right now. Um okay
slide four.
So we're envisioning this as four steps
where uh trainees are moving from lower
risk to higher risk groups and no one is
able to complete their practi their
supervised practice without having real
client contact. So uh just to start with
step one. So we're envisioning about 30
hours with well participants in a
retreat or peer support model where
there's preparation and integration for
every participant. Obviously, this is
going to require a new law since um
that's not an option, but I I really
feel like this is a is a developmentally
appropriate place for people to start
and could look similar to what they're
doing already in Colorado and Oregon.
So, step two, um this would be about 20
hours as the second chair or the second
facilitator on at least two co-f
facilitated cases with a licensed with a
licensed permitted provider. Um, I would
recommend that these be low acuity cases
only, ideally nicotine use disorder or
major depressive disorder, assuming that
we can get that into the um, legislation
for the spring. Um, I would say that
PTSD and other substance use disorders
should be excluded at this stage. that
developmentally they're not really
appropriate where uh if the main
facilitator's out of the room to go to
the bathroom, the trainee is not really
in a appropriate person to be able to um
kind of support in the event of a
crisis. Uh about step three about 12
hours of group practicum. Really liked
that recommendation and I think given
that this is likely going to be a common
model here in New Mexico that students
should that trainee should have an
opportunity to practice that. Um and
then step four, this is for the licensed
provider only have an opportunity to do
10 hours as the lead facilitator with a
licensed provider as the second chair.
Um, so part of this would require that
there be a training permit created and I
imagine that the training permit would
be issued at the completion of step one
and it would cover steps two, three plus
the consultation period. 2, three, and
four plus the consultation period. And
so this really gives trainees a lawful
pathway to get their required client
contact. uh and I think it it nicely
mirrors the associate lensure structures
that were supported in the Colorado
analysis and it also signals to the
public that a permittee um a permit
practices under supervision. Um
something I would recommend for these
placements during this process. The
current draft requires that all hours be
held in an approved healing center. Um
which I think can potentially be a
bottleneck for rural trainees. I I
really like the idea of the apprentice
apprenticeship or the site supervisor
model similar to what they do for
counseling lensure or direct entry
midwiffery. Um and that may be worth
discussing with the counter question of
who is going to vet site supervisors. Um
and ultimately I think that's a
committee for the decision for the
committee.
Um so this is where the financial
reality that I named at the start does
its work. So, we're looking at a 62 to
72-hour practicum with structured
checkpoints that keep the quality bar
while cutting the cost burden of 120hour
requirement nearly in half.
Um, yeah. So, that's the practicum and
then slide five, if you could move on to
that one. Jorge,
>> got it.
>> So, the consultation sign off. um sort
of the problem the current draft's 10
hours of mentoring never require that
the permedi um have has seen a client.
So consultation groups in Colorado um
have allowed completion of these hours
by attendance alone and um I would
suggest that tying sign off to presented
cases really closes that gap. Um, and in
the in place of the 10 hours, I would
recommend 20 to 30 hours of supervision
or consultation during the permit period
in addition to the practicum. Um, and
that signoff would require that a
trainee present at least two cases where
the permit personally worked with um
using the regulated medicine with
standard evaluation forms on each. And
each presentation would need to not just
be like, oh, Jennifer did really well.
It would need to be a formal
biocschosocial case conceptualization
with presenting concerns, risk factors,
supportive factors, treatment
considerations and after care. Um this
idea came to us through the memory memor
uh and and Boulder which was developed
under the leadership of one of the lead
principal investigators in the MAPS MDMA
clinical trials. Um and that group is of
course among the most experienced
psychedelic therapists in the country
and they use the two case u model to
sign off on their consultes and I would
say that the two cases really gives us
an adequate basis for final evaluation.
Um you know and just kind of one last
addition there would be also an end of
life checkpoint. So before serving end
of life participants independently at
least one co-f facilitated end of life
case needs to be um they a trainee would
need to do one case with the one end of
life case and then at least present one
in supervision.
Um next slide.
So these were just some open questions
that I came across in putting this
together. first indications and volume.
Um the current indications really limit
our patient pool and therefore
placements and training and trainees
getting through it. Um obviously major
depressive disorder is proposed for 2027
uh generalized anxiety disorder might
take a little bit longer but um broader
indications I think that would
materially change the practicum
feasibility. Uh second, addiction. Uh do
we need a dedicated substance use
disorder plan? Third, instructor vetting
who approved site supervisors if
placements are decoupled from training
programs. And fourth, just the sort of
um you know, assuming that the FDA
approval arrives with reduced therapy
support requirements, uh longer state
programs are probably going to face
enrollment issues. And I think an
84-hour standard is probably easier to
sustain. um and 150 when compared to
training programs uh sorry when um drug
companies only require 20 to 30 hours of
training. So that's what I have and I'm
happy to answer any questions or if
there are folks who would like to add
anything. Um thanks for your time.
>> Thank you an and yes this opens it up
for more questions here from uh the
public uh here. Uh yes, thank you so
much for this. This was um really great
to see what um Colorado has been doing
and uh you know this is the thing we
need to have more information about what
what what is out there right now. Um and
we don't want to get stuck in our own
silo here on just kind of going over
what we need to do here in New Mexico.
But, uh, you guys are out there, you
know, uh, had this out there in Colorado
for
quite a few years now. And so, we should
be, um, actually learning from what you
guys have been
going through basically. So, I really
appreciate appreciate what you've done
here, Ann. This is really wonderful. So,
I'm going to open this up to any um,
questions that people may have here.
Brenda Ian has his hand up.
>> Okay. All right. Ian,
>> hi. I just wanted to say thank you again
for your presentation. It was really
nice. Um I did have one question. So I
just either clarification if I'm
misunderstanding or um we can explore it
further. But you have to go through um
like you said I can't remember the
phrase you said but essentially easier
cases right like the lighter loads
nicotine disorder um if approved major
depressive disorder and then um they
would go through
harder ones before getting approved or
would they just be approved for lenture
without ever having um
like experienced some of those more
difficult case situations.
Erica, your mic has been enabled. You
can unmute yourself when you're ready.
Sorry, it always makes me do something
strange. Um, I had a question about
practicum. I was curious at what point
is the student eligible to start
practicum? So, do they have to have been
through a certain amount of didactic
first or is it um didactic needs to be
complete and then they start um their
practicum?
as as far as I know as practicum goes um
the dactic seems to always come first.
Uh we in the education and training
that's usually what had what the the
protocol is because you need that
foundation of the education part of it
and then uh uh practicum comes comes
later because you need to have that uh
education foundation first. So, uh we're
still kind of looking at um you know the
hours what will be uh implemented there
as far as you know the education and
training goes. So uh usually practicum
usually comes later.
>> Okay. So in full didactic is completed
in full before practicum begins. Just
clarifying.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I would imagine so because
uh anyone who's done any type of uh you
know clinical training uh it you want to
be able to uh have people that um you
know are educated and know what to
expect instead of going in like okay if
they're observing or uh if they have uh
working with a a client they need to
have that foundation.
>> Okay. I was just curious because in
social work it's partial um partial
dactic. It's not the full program before
entering practicum. But thank thank you
that helps.
>> Yeah. And I think it's because too this
is this is new
>> and uh so we want to uh we want to be as
safe as possible as far as all of the uh
rules and regulations go too.
>> Sure. Thank you.
>> Hi. Hey, I apologize. Um, I did someone
answer Ian's question. I got booted off
the meeting. It was error on my part,
I'm sure.
>> Uh, [snorts] no, we didn't answer uh
Ian's question. I think that was
directed to you to you, Ann.
>> Yes. So, the the the plan really is, you
know, I mean, in terms of as we how we
educate and train new clinicians, we
usually work from a lower acuity to a
higher acuity model. And so um I think
there I think that that is what makes
sense developmentally in terms of this
training program. And so that's why I am
recommending yes that people start out
with lower acuity conditions and then
you know as they're doing their
supervised consultation hours that they
would um you know be able to work on
more complex cases.
>> Perfect. Thank you. I just wanted to
make sure that they would eventually
deal with complex cases before they
were, you know, like fully licensed by
to practice by themselves.
>> Yeah. I think as soon as they're in the
consultation um phase that they've
completed the um lower acuity and that
they've had the um
um super supervision 10 hours and the
group that I think they could certainly
take on more difficult cases.
>> Thank you. Uh who's next?
>> We have uh Lisa. Your mic has been
enabled. Unmute when you're ready.
Um, thank you and great presentation.
Thank you for putting this together. I
completely agree on reducing the amount
of deductic hours. Uh, looking at
Colorado program, we see a lot of people
um going through redundant content. Um,
a few things that I am missing in your
presentation is the hours for
integration and group work as well as
the dosing. Is that part of the general
core skills or
is this supposed to be somewhere else?
>> Um, thank you for that question, Lisa.
Um, we are still looking at um uh
finding out what the other committees
are doing and and working that in um as
uh we go along with education and
training. uh as far as integration and
all of that that will be in the training
modules
uh that we'll be um putting together. As
far as uh everything else goes as far as
safety, ethics and and all of those
other modules that need to be in the
training will be there. Uh it's part of
the core competencies of the education
and training. um and it's really a
staple really to have those ethics and
safety in there. So to um not you know
keep going over these uh the
competencies they are in the
competencies as far as the the
department of health goes and uh other
things too. I mean uh are we
we got to look at things that we're
missing too? I know there's I I can see
there's a lot of redundancy in in a lot
of these other programs and we we're we
really want to um not uh skip over
things, but then again, we want to make
sure that uh we're doing our due
diligence as far as training training
goes. Also too, um as we go along with
all of these meetings, um creating
standards for the education and training
would be um optimal in in focusing on uh
the population of of uh clinicians and
practitioners out there. So, we really
need to uh as we go along, this is still
getting shaped and shaved and built on.
So, we're really working hard at trying
to make sure that what we're going to be
providing for the program is um yeah,
there will be maybe some limitations,
maybe there there won't be, but we're
we're uh doing our due diligence and
trying to find out what we really need
to uh start to build on in this program
for education and training.
And who's next? Thanks.
Yes,
>> Dr. Lita, your mic has been enabled.
Unmute yourself when you're ready.
>> Thank you so much. Um, thank you so much
and that was a great presentation with
some great solutions and um very
comprehensive. Um, so thank you for
that. And you know there was a comment
about finishing all the dididactics
before going into practicum. I'm finding
that combining
practicum with didactic tends to be very
effective. Um in my program we do the
first trimester the first three months
in um purely in preparation
ethics uh indigenous practices
self-care foundations
um traumainformed care and really
getting the practitioner going through
their own selfdiscovery
because a practitioner who is
traumatized themselves sitting for
another traumatized individual does not
yield good results usually. And so
really paying attention to those codes
of ethics that we have in our program of
holding the practitioner to the highest
standard of um their own trauma pro uh
trauma processing and self-care
and without any medicine and community
building and um group coaching. Then we
go into practicum for their own um
self-experient.
I find that to be that to be essential
for us to understand what these
medicines are and what they do before
sitting for others. Um and then for 6
months after
their selfexperiential
practicum um which we calculated to be
16 hours
um after that we do 6 months of
integration
in small group format. Um that is
essential and also with didactics for
another six months. Um I find that many
educational programs
they leave out experientials out of the
equation um for some time and that
decreases engagement and retention of
material and when we include
experientials as we go along. I'll give
you a very simple example
of breath work. Um in our first module
we talk about uh we did a dactus and
with ev everything is evidence-based
with meditation and breath work. That's
the first conscious life practice that
they get introduced to and they're held
accountable to doing it in their own
life and how and what is coming up for
them from that lens of meditation and
breath work. But if we were, you know,
when they do it
they and they stick with it, that's the
only time they can really speak to a
client about it and its benefits. And so
um the experiential part I feel like is
always an evolving part. It's always
there at least with what we do. Every
program is different of course, but I
think it's really important especially
in psychedelics
to um to combine to combine maybe not
from the very beginning but at some
point maybe in the midpoint uh for there
to be a practicum opportunity
um they gain a lot from it. Um and
that's the the surveys and evaluations
that we sent out was very positive in
their professional development in
personal development and so forth. Um
and thank you.
>> Uh thank you Dr. Alita. Um I appreciate
the experiential part of it uh very much
so. Um however um oftent times with um
uh therapists um often have to do their
own work before they even uh that would
be the ideal, you know, for them to do
their own work for themselves before
they even attempt to uh uh take on
clients because this has always been a
sticking point for uh in the past uh
this is what I've heard that um some
people become clinicians and have never
done uh any of their own therapy. Uh so
experiential is is very important. Um
and I think it would be an important uh
part of uh especially people who are uh
who do not um uh you know or have not uh
done any any type of this work and that
you're offering them, you know, an
opportunity to uh discover uh things
about themselves that they can be ready
to uh be there and present uh for other
people. Um, uh, go ahead again, Dr.
Fatmi.
>> Yeah, I I agree with you that it that,
you know, for us to then, um,
they need to have shown competencies
before
we can say yes, you can now move on to a
setting with pra supervised practicum
with a client. Um so I do agree with you
on that for sure that people have to go
through their own journey first. Yeah.
Thank you.
>> Thank you doctor. Um who is next? Is it
Kate Hawk? Are you next?
>> Hey dear mic has been enabled. Unmute
yourself when you're ready.
>> Oh I Okay, I'm unmuted again. Yes. Um,
wow. There's so much I could agree with
and so much to this conversation. I
would say thank you an for what you
presented. Um, you know, if we had to
decide in this meeting, I'd say and that
was it. It's like, okay, we can live
with that. We'll, you know, we'll see
how it goes. And I hear what you know
what you said, Lita. It's like there's
so much that's really important in doing
this work with our personal experience
and group support and having time to
think things through and having some
practice and then you know then learning
some more. Um, and I think
realistically, uh, especially if we're
looking at psilocybin
quite possibly getting rescheduled next
year, uh, I think, you know, let's make
sure everybody has the essentials and
let's also encourage more indepth
enriched programs that won't be required
for the basics, but hopefully will be
available, you know, more and more and
ongoing, you know, professional
um peer support and uh you know learning
learning together. I'm still learning
after all these decades. Uh I'd also
want to mention the uh brain futures
study and I know Dominic you've talked
to those folks and uh people are
familiar with they've just studied all
these programs and an you know you've
been looking at things that have studied
multiple programs. Um, so I'm hoping
they should have
something available out of their study
to look at this month just as you know
as a rationale and backup for how we are
choosing these and I appreciate and I
appreciate that you did have like these
came out of studies and groups that were
you know there was a lot of input there.
So my question is how much time do we
have because I know we want to have
something for the advisory board to
approve and what the next meeting is in
some weeks. So, do we have that window
to work with what we already have and
have the people who really want to focus
on this put all of our best information
together and come up with something that
we can feel solid about?
>> Thank you, Kate. Um, uh, Dominic, um,
can you answer to that?
>> Yeah, thank you, Brenda. And Kate, thank
you. I appreciate it. And actually with
both of the things that have been
presented today is we're actually not
very far off. I think there's a few
misconceptions and I'm not going to go
into them right now because we really
want to hear more from people and and I
actually don't think that we're very far
off. So the department is as I mentioned
this morning during the board meeting is
planning on moving forward with uh a
hearing so a rules hearing at the end of
August. Um, and so that really doesn't
leave a whole lot more time at this
point. And and a lot of what we've
already done, what you're talking about
was collecting what the topics are,
collecting what they are and what it you
or what they should be. And what I think
really is kind of happening here is um
just some some different ideas as far as
approach as far as how the training
should be set up, but they're not really
very different um from what from what we
actually have already in the proposed
rules and some about length of time and
and as I've said before, as we're you
know, we're happy to talk about
adjusting those lengths of time. And so
it might actually be beneficial to um uh
to be able to show what we have there
and say what topics are we missing and
then talk a little bit about what type
you know how many hours do we need do we
need to adjust. Um because for example
talking about the practicum we have in
the proposed rules that we had shared is
that it includes the ability for those
students to not just observe but also to
be um facilitating for example or acting
in the practitioner role. And so that's
already in there. And the main reason we
didn't break it out into separate um
like separate sections like saying oh 20
hours for this 20 hours for that is
because you are going to have different
needs depending on the students. So for
example, going through a practicum or
your internship as a counselor, what
really happens is you have to complete
those hours and as you grow proficient,
the people who are supervising you
actually start giving you those harder
and harder cases. And that should really
be the situation here as well where
we're not trying to define in an
artificial way. Here are separate
individual blocks. this is a part of how
the educational program works with the
student to ensure the best experience
possible for them. And so that's really,
you know, to to really kind of talk
about that that really fits in because
when we look at the model that an
presented, which is a great model in
many ways, you know, it still comes up
to between 146 to 56 or 58 hours. um and
in total and that's between all the
practicum and not including the final 20
to 30 hours of the consultation and if
you look at the model that we had
presented is it really including that
falls right within that same time frame.
So it's really just a question of how do
we adjust? Um so but time frame wise and
even after we do um you know put out
what the draft rule is for the hearing
as we've talked about before with the
previous set of hearings we could still
make adjustments especially if it's as
far as some of those hours or adding in
a topic area that was missed those sort
of things. Um so it's really not very
far off from what people are talking
about. Um it's just a question of uh you
know are do we have all the topics that
are needed and do we need to adjust the
hours for example on the dactic somewhat
and so with that I'll turn it back over
to you Brenda. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Thank you for explaining that
Dominic. Yeah. Uh I I think um the hours
and and that kind of thing. I think
we're coming closer and closer to um a
more uh definite number on what that's
going to to look like and uh you know
and uh creating a standardized structure
where uh you know where the teaching and
the curriculum are going to uh fall in
line with what the the DO has in the
competencies. So I think what what
however
you know uh teaching style that you have
it just it has to have these elements in
there these uh actual subject matters in
there in the modules in order to be
approved uh by I guess the um would it
be approved by the education uh uh for
uh clinical practitioners or will do do
be part of that?
You know, that's that's a question that
I have.
>> I'm sorry, Brenda. Can you repeat that?
I'm not quite sure what you're
>> Yes. Uh well, will um who will be
overseeing
uh the uh curriculum for to for the
competencies for the DO?
>> Gotcha. I understand. That's actually
why those are the educational programs
and they have to have that third party
review.
>> Okay. Yeah, that thank you very much
because I was just kind of, you know, I
knew there was a a third party in there,
but um um I just wanted to know
uh
all the things that they will be doing
as far as uh oversight of uh the
education and training.
Yeah, I mean basically uh the
educational programs they'll submit to
the department all of the the criteria
of what their curricula is um how their
their for example the CVS or resumes of
the instructors what their plan for the
syllabi are um all of that but they
still also will have and need to have
that third-party evaluation that's
looking to ensure that the curriculum is
implemented with fidelity uh that it's
verified um and and then that will also
get submitted to the department for
review and then the department will be
the the um the ones who actually certify
then that training program.
>> Thank you for reviewing that because I
think because I I I kind of knew it in
the back of my head, but um I I think I
had some
uh parts in there that some questions
that weren't really um connecting for
me. So, thank you for going over that.
Uh, so, um, anybody else have any other
questions or, um, any comments? Uh, I
see Larry, you're, uh, who's next? Is it
Chris?
>> Yes, that would be Dr. Larry.
>> Larry. Okay.
>> Hi, Brenda. Thank you. Thank you for the
opportunity. Um, uh, and I thanks for
all the work you put into that. It's
actually really quite quite amazing and
I think it takes us a lot closer to
where we need to um need to go. I just
want to make a couple of comments
particular. I agree with everybody about
people need to do their own work that I
actually think that that's up to the
programs. It's outside of the didactic.
They need to say when you're doing this
training, we recommend that you have
your own practice, that you do
self-care. And so I think it's outside
of the hours, but I think it's essential
for the programs. Um I for the the way
that you've outlined the number of hours
I think this gives us a template to
actually have meaningful conversations.
I mean we people have been saying okay
you need a hundred you need 50 you need
whatever but by looking at this we can
go well okay which of these need more
which of them need less and I really
like them and um I I agree with Dom I
think that the it's not far from what is
written there but I honestly think this
is better because it's more specific and
I think that this could be used as a
template as we move forward to to make
some decisions like that would be really
[snorts] good. I I found it very helpful
to have it broken down to those smaller
smaller parts. Um similarly for the
practicum um I think this takes us well
beyond what anyone's done in anywhere
else in the country. I mean it's really
if we can institute this it you know for
instance I you know in Colorado when you
do the supervision you don't really have
to do anything quite honestly you can
like sit there in a room be one of 20
people on a Zoom thing you do that for
40 hours and you're done. I mean to be
blunt about it um by requiring that
people have to present two cases it's
much more like a you know an educational
model where we feel like people have
demonstrated the knowledge and what I
like about the supervision is I I mean
the practicum is I see two points for
that. I see the co-f facilitation where
that's being done and you're being
evaluated directly with someone doing
that and then I see the the next part.
So, I I really like the um the gradiated
uh model and I think that we can be
really taking the lead in having a a
quality practicum that's I think
stronger than ones that are present in
in Colorado and Oregon. So, anyway,
thank you so much Ann. I'm really
excited to see this moving forward.
>> Thank you. Um, next I believe is Chris
and then we'll go into the chat um after
this to let's see what comments are are
there.
>> Chris, your mic has been enabled. Unmute
yourself when you're ready.
>> Hi all. Well, for those that don't know
me, I'm Chris Caldwell, founder
executive director for End of Life
Psychedelic Care. So we are primarily an
educational
organization and we've trained
approximately 700 students to date. So I
do have a few questions. I have uh
Brenda really quick question first. Um
is this subcommittee responsible for uh
determining CES?
>> Um no not not right now. Um I I think
that would uh definitely be there. Oh
yes, most definitely. Uh so um I think
that's um going to come later on. Uh as
far as uh the education and training
goes um uh yes there's been some
discussion about CE CEUs and that sort
of thing uh and getting credited hours
for that. uh especially for uh every you
know two years when you have to renew
your license and um you're you're
needing CEUs um and you know as far as
uh uh psilocybin goes uh you know the
ongoing training with that is uh I think
essential uh with this particular
program.
>> All right thank you. Um so yeah a a much
longer sort of comment and question. Um
for those who participated in the end of
life subcommittee the other day I was
arguing for EOL being an adjunct
training. So something in addition um to
the the core training and as such um had
recommended
um nine competencies
and effectively 19 hours of live um
instruction which does include didactic
plus experiential plus breakout
sessions. A lot of interactivity in
that. Um, and then plus at least 5 hours
on homework, pre-recorded, um, and other
things that we just couldn't fit into
the the live sessions. So, I'm curious.
Um the program here is recommending 10
to 15
um which arguably could get somebody
started but I don't think it's going to
be sufficient
um for someone who wants to work closer
to the end of life because we've talked
about this being a pretty major
continuum from initial diagnosis uh all
the way to the close to end of life. So,
I would question that. But I think
[clears throat]
um more importantly um Brenda and and
Dom I was wondering you know we've been
talking a lot about reciprocity and I'm
not sure I totally understand it so
forgive me for that but if um if you
want to have these programs in place to
kick off the actual delivery of services
by the end of the year and you're you're
um allowing reciprocity from Oregon and
and um Colorado training organizations
they don't provide end of life modules
sufficient to train anybody. They you
know I teach one teach one for Lisa.
Thank you. But you know that's a single
a single session. So I'm really curious
as to how that may be handled. Oh I and
one one more comment though if you don't
mind. So I can I concede Larry I concede
that you know u folding the end of life
portion or module into or modules
because I think you said 10 to 15 hours
into the core makes it easier on the
practicum and supervisory
requirements. So I I will say say that
but yeah the reciprocity is what's uh
really interesting to me.
>> Thank you Chris. I you know um I think
after because I attended Larry's meeting
too the um uh yesterday that uh this is
this is something that uh yes should uh
definitely
uh be in there because I think this is
something that um is uh essential even
if uh someone who hasn't um had any
experience uh with learning uh end of
life uh care or any type of study. uh
having something in uh the education
part in one of the modules I think uh
would be uh uh one thing that that could
be in in there to just even as uh to
introduce people to this because it it
really has not been mentioned a whole
lot I think in other programs. Um the
other thing too is substance use uh
programs uh like for instance uh I have
a license in the substance uh an
addiction and uh even though that that's
a separate thing you know how is that
going to look like for um you know the
psilocybin program. So there's still a
lot on the table here to be discussed
and um put into uh learning modules as
well. So, uh, yeah. Well, thank you.
Thank you for that, Chris. I I really
appreciate that.
>> Okay. Next,
Denali, your mic has been enabled. You
may unmute yourself.
>> Hi. Um, thanks everybody. Um, and thank
you Ann for the presentation. I thought
it was really helpful to conceptualize
some of [clears throat]
Yeah. how to bridge um you know where we
are in the draft with where um you know
would really put us um [clears throat]
at the cutting edge of um both you know
quality and accessibility and
>> [clears throat]
>> um safety. I think that you've struck a
really strong balance. A couple of
things I I appreciate the department um
you know perspective that we're we're
close with the regulations. a couple of
things jump out as as missing between
what was presented and and what's in the
drafts at least the version that's been
sent to the public. Um big ones I think
especially given the conversation we had
in end of life yesterday is that um you
know specific if we cannot create a
specific
um certification requirement for people
to provide um care to vulnerable
specifically uniquely vulnerable
populations um which I I think was the
perspective I heard then I think it's
that much more important that we have
specific didactic um requirements for
those indications. So I think from what
I what's been presented, you know, that
would be substance use disorder, end of
life, suicidality, PTSD, that that be
incorporated into the curriculum
requirements.
Um, and then I I do really like this
permit, like the training permit um
model. I but that would require
incorporation within um within
regulations. So, um it it's a new permit
type, you know, whether we call it a
training permit or a practitioner and
training permit or some other name. Um
it would be a new uh a new permit type.
And I do think it's important that it
have a DO permit designation because I
think what's key to the affordability
part of that model is that then that
person can count as um one of the two
practitioners that's required under
other sections of the department.
um regulations.
Um, and then one final thought that I
think is unique to us in New Mexico.
I've been thinking a lot about you know
whether we need some safety parameters
around ways that people yes we need an
expansion um for practicums to be
feasible um for them to be you know
operated on on well patients you know
those without qualifying conditions and
and within the training program you know
educators and and students um having
that experience that's very needed and
you know I appreciate from the present
presentation and and consensus in
conversation, the need for experience
with people who do have qualifying
conditions. I I think both are needed
and specifically within that qualifying
condition base, I I think we maybe need
to think about parameters for safety um
about whether you know the the
educational institution can certify
um a clinician or sorry certify a
diagnosis and medically clear someone
just because I think there
there's perhaps an inherent incentive
for people to be cleared.
so that people can get their educational
hours.
>> Thank you, Denali. That's um yes, I I
think that uh what you're saying here is
um having a a permit after, you know,
people have gone through this program.
Um you know, uh I I think that's uh a a
very um
I I think that is a very important part
for this uh because I I think that um as
far as uh going through a um program
like this, this is a it's such a special
thing and especially with um uh learning
and going through all of the education
modules and finally like coming out at
the end of you know the program was 120
or 50 hours is is quite a bit. Um, while
you were talking, I was thinking to
myself, I thought, you know, with these
specialty types of things, um,
especially especially end of life or
substance use, um, maybe, um, having
some type of, uh, internship with people
that are going through the program that
want to go into,
uh, for example, end of life. uh maybe
the you know having some kind of other
um specialized training in that as uh
like an intern. So um I don't know I was
just thinking about that idea while you
were talking that that could also be a
possibility but then again you know we
you know uh you know you know how much
time is this going to take how much is
this going to cost? I mean, I think
we're um maybe that's for um uh for
later on as the program matures and
develops. Uh but I think having um some
of these other special things in uh the
learning modules are um at least giving
students an idea of uh these the other
conditions that uh they could possibly
work with if they if they choose to
specialize in these types of things. Um,
so, okay, I'll stop talking now. Um, uh,
who is next?
>> We have Chris.
>> Chris.
>> Hello everyone. Um, thank you an for
the uh presentation and I just wanted to
say that I
um think that's a much more balanced
approach. Um I do like that in that
model um practitioners and facilitators
are trained together and have the same
requirements. I think um that is a big
piece of that and I think that training
side by side with clinical pra
facilitators in Colorado is important um
for me
um
I
think
um
you know going down the rabbit hole of
individual training for every qualified
condition is going to be challenging,
especially as that list expands there.
Each are going to have their
um issues. And I also think that if we
put too many training requirements
um
for each of those qualifying conditions
into the regulations, it's going to
limit accessibility through just how
much training people have to do. And so
I
although I am concerned that the current
regulations maybe don't have enough
um training around PTSD or uh trauma.
I
think
it would be better for me to work with
veteran organizations and people like
firefighters from plant medicine to um
train and vet individual organizations
who then we can uh refer specific
patients to. Um, one question I do have
is if we if we change these
requirements,
uh, are we going to look at changing our
reciprocity since we don't have any
instate
certified programs? [snorts] Will
will um, people have to take additional
practicum to receive reciprocity? And we
may have covered this, but I just wanted
to double check.
>> Well, that that kind of stumped me a
little bit. Uh, so um I think we're
still um you know, we have uh some
uh idea of what reciprocity will look
like. Uh if uh Dominic wanted to weigh
in on that a little bit more um
I'll hand it over to you Dominic.
>> Sure. I mean as far as reciprocity I
mean again what we really have right now
is we're just stating that they have to
uh that they have to do a crosswalk of
the curriculum of whatever ends up being
required in New Mexico. So in other
words, showing that there is comparable
coverage in each of the areas that'll be
required in New Mexico. And uh once that
is there, then the other piece would be
and this is to match the same things
that we're requiring even in state up
until December 31st of 27 is that 40
contact hours with patients to ensure
that they actually do have some
interactions uh with patients uh through
their program. um or even if it's been
beyond it, if their program didn't have
quite as many hours um from some of the
other areas. And so that's actually the
requirement for it. So if we did change
what the requirements in the curriculum
in New Mexico are, it would not change
that aspect of the recip.
>> Thank you.
>> Okay. Um
>> looks
>> like we have Dr. Larry again.
>> Larry. Okay.
>> Good. Thank you. I I just wanted to
convey a little bit what came from the
end of life committee. Um uh yesterday I
mean there was a pretty strong feeling
that that that end of life is a distinct
enough set that really does need
specific training. Many of the programs
in Colorado have just a number a few
number of hours. So I think if we did
reciprocity um for now they people
probably would need to do an additional
module somewhere to um uh to do that. As
far as long-term I think um I think that
there could be two approaches in New
Mexico given we only right now have four
indications and personally I think
substance use will be probably the least
one. I mean, I think having people um
spend, you know, 10, 15 hours on end of
life, I I would advocate would be
reasonable to have it core, but I think
they're very much going to continue to
be a need for programs like Chris's
because there's people who are going to
have trained in Colorado and Oregon and
will need that. And honestly, you know,
if we do have end of life as strong an
area here, as I suspect it will be, um I
would hope that there would be um Chris
a role for them to get more training at
programs around the country, including
yours in end of life because honestly 15
hours is even not that long if that's
going to be your your your focus. So
that that's that's my thought on
balancing the is it integrated or is it
extra.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you, Larry.
Um,
>> next we have Next we have Lisa. Lisa,
your mic has been enabled. You may
unmute yourself.
>> Thank you. Um, I just wanted to agree
with uh what Chris was saying earlier on
the specialized training and redundancy
of that. Considering that licensed
practitioners and providers are already
licensed and experienced, I don't see a
need for them to go uh through extra
training and PTSD or depression because
it's a giving that all the trained in in
that uh modality and as a socipation
or administration
in general uses
nondirective approach.
I would assume they would not really
work with those people and provide
therapy during the skill set session
itself and most of the work will be done
after the session. So and at this point
I think they all disqualified to do
that. Um I also agree with Chris Cwell
about a need for standalone training on
end of life. I think end of life is a
very niche area that requires additional
training and what we offering in our
general program is not enough to make
someone a specialist in that department.
Um maybe generalist yes but not a
specialist. Um and also I would love to
see and I made I made a comment um in
the chat. would love to see a separate
module for prescribers that would focus
on prescribing and diagnosing
clients.
>> Thank you. Um
uh let's see um who's next?
>> I see Dominic's hand up.
>> Yeah, thank you. Um, I just wanted to go
back to a point that was raised earlier
about a training permit. And I just want
to to to note that that really wouldn't
be necessary with the model that we have
and the way that we put the practitioner
aspect in there. Um, just because that
already would be covered as them being a
registered student with an educational
program where they have that ability to
be a part of those training sessions
including to conduct them under
supervision. So that sort of fits in
with that training part. Now Denali, you
brought up, I think it was Denali,
please forgive me if I am
misremembering, but you brought up an
interesting part about them uh the
students at that point counting towards
part of the ratio. And we can definitely
take a look at that if that would be
after they've completed so many hours to
be a part of that rather than needing to
create an entire other permit or
certification level. But we could
definitely look at that and uh I'll take
that on back as well. So, thank you. I
just wanted to to present that because
that's already was part of the idea as
far as not needing another permit with
that practicum because those students
already will have that kind of
protection ability to be there as a part
of being registered as a student with an
educational program.
>> Thank you, Dominic. And I'll uh let's
see. I'll take the the the last two and
then I want to try to get into uh some
of the comments in the the chat after
Ian. Uh so next I think is Erica. Is
that it?
>> Yes, Erica, your mic is enabled.
>> You may unmute yourself, Erica.
>> There we go. Um, so I had a question
about the document that was sent out to
the public and there's been some
confusion among us out here. And then
during the last meeting, it sounded like
there was some confusion um in the
committee as well. So I just wanted some
clarification on the reciprocity because
there are two different dates that have
been set. Um, one is the end of 2026 and
one is June 2027.
And I was wondering if I'm just missing
the difference between those two dates,
reciprocity for something different.
Number one. And number two, I would
suggest that um the June the mid June
date would be much more feasible um for
many of us who are um you know quite
busy but very invested and interested in
this.
>> I I think we we we did um come to a
consensus on June 27th uh the year 20 No
June 27th but next year. Yeah, it was.
>> Yeah, it's December 31st of 27. And so,
Eric, Erica, you probably were seeing an
earlier version where what we really
said is we put it in as a placeholder
because we wanted to have the
conversation and the decision across the
board was um those dates that you really
were seeing for reciprocity out of state
and for the instate programs, for
example, all we put it all to December
31st of 27. So that way it allows the
time for the infrastructure build.
>> Thank you so much. That means a lot.
>> Absolutely. And that that's a part of it
too is sometimes we have to put a
placeholder in to have the
conversations. That one specifically or
those dates were placeholders. So we're
following so closely. Yeah.
>> Some of us are following so closely.
We're like
I appreciate that. Thank you.
>> You're welcome.
>> Yeah. The post keeps moving, right? We
just we gota we got to kind of do it
that way. Uh thank you Dominic. Uh
anything you want to add Dominic while
you have
>> No, I had just put my hand up to answer
that question.
>> Okay. Thank you. Um and uh uh we'll take
uh Ian next and then I'm going to go
into the chat and
uh uh say whatever people have to say in
the chat. Go ahead Ian.
>> Yeah. So, I [clears throat] just wanted
to bring up because I've heard it come
up a few times um about people wanting
more some sort of certification or
specialization training. Um I just kind
of wanted to remind people that
generally like um organizations of
people that practice. So like um
eventually the psilocybin assisted
therapy association or some other
professional association will end up
creating like certifications like we see
with nursing and you can become a
psychiatric mental health nurse. Um you
can become a critical care nurse. all
nurses can perform the job of all other
nurses, but they can take a
specialization
route where it's then like an like an
endorsement saying this person has
completed extra training. Um, but that
doesn't need to be created here at the
Department of Health. That will come
naturally as the field progresses.
>> Thank you, Ian. I really appreciate that
because it's it's the same for um us
therapists as well. Uh for instance, um
I'm you know, I'm certified in autism
and ADHD.
uh you know there's uh certain things
that you you can go into and specialize
in like uh other types of modalities for
um for therapists uh such as like EMDR
and things of that nature. So, uh, as
far as like specializing and getting
trained and all of that, I think, um, if
you already are, you know, in the
medical field, mental health field, you
already have a really great foundation
for um, uh, taking this program. and
that uh uh I the reciprocity part uh
should be uh definitely taken uh if
you've already had uh other training in
in psychedelics in general. So yeah, I
think this is um um still developing and
still needs uh we're we're getting there
closer and closer. So, I wanted to go
back to the chat. Um, uh, let's see the
beginning of the, uh, meeting here. It
says, uh, this is from, uh, Paul Walton.
Uh, and on behalf of, um, Amy Wong, uh,
could not be here, but asked if, uh, she
could make a comment. says, "Thank you
for the opportunity to offer my
perspective on what should be defined as
a credible psilocybin facilitator pro
training program. First, the curriculum
must be clinically and trauma informed.
Facilitators need sufficient knowledge
of trauma, disassociation, psychiatric
risk, grief, medical concerns, substance
use, and the populations they may serve,
including people experiencing
depression, PTSD, substance use
concerns, serious illness, and end of
life distress. They must be able to
recognize complexities and individual uh
vulnerability, understand the limits of
their scope, and know when to consult,
refer, pause, or decline to proceed.
Second, ethics must be woven throughout
the program, not confined to a single
module. Students should repeatably
engage with consent, power, touch,
boundaries, dual relationships, cultural
humility, conflicts of interest,
heightened suggestability,
ethical com competence, means being able
to perceive risks, tolerate uncertainty,
seek consultation, receive feedback, and
repair harm. It is an ongoing practice.
Third, programs need a meaningful
practicum. Students should be observed
practicing preparation, screening,
difficult conversations, boundary
setting, crisis response, facilitation,
and integration. Competence should be
demonstrated through supervised
experience not assumed from attendance
or written assignments. Periodic
practicum based competency review at
some regular interview could help
facilitate keep these skills active.
Fourth, admissions and evaluation should
assess interpersonal maturity, emotional
regulation, self-awareness,
self-reflective accountability, and the
capacity to receive and integrate
feedback. Facilitators should also
participate in ongoing consultation or
peer consultation groups. These
practices demonstrate readiness to hold
responsibility for vulnerable people.
Ultimately, safety is not merely a
protocol surrounding the intervention.
Safety is an essential ingredient in the
intervention itself. A strong program
prepares facilitators to bring sound
judgment, accountability, humility, and
respect for the full personhood of every
participant.
So, I want to thank Amy for for writing
that. that encapsulates
all the things that therapists need to
know when they're they're doing the work
and uh this program
um I hope will be able to
>> have that in there in our modules.
Um let's see. Um
uh this is uh previously from Ian. Uh
just a clarification approved new
qualifying conditions like major
depressive disorder will not require new
legislation. The board may recommend new
qualifying conditions for the
secretary's approval assuming there is s
sufficient evidence.
And then we go into um
uh let's see
uh the first trimester uh this is by uh
uh Dr. Fatmi. The first trimester is a
CPPA is didactic and personal discovery
trauma processing and then we go into
practicum then we go back into dactic.
So, she's basically saying what she said
previously to um have this be kind of
like a um dact kind of like an amalgam
of didactic and practicum in the same um
uh learning experience throughout the
program. Um
uh Vanessa says, "I've been working on
EOL for uh 20 plus years. one EOL
session uh live does not seem to be
enough truly to understand this complex
time.
Um and previously said prep and
integration would be covered in the
treatment modules and the core skills
and ethics section.
Um Lisa uh talked about I'd love to see
a module for prescribers as well uh and
included well uh participants and your
suggestions as peer support or retreat
style and what is experiential was um my
understanding.
And then um we have uh Jim Dodson.
Um I am a patient who experienced a
successful outcome from this program
four years ago. By choosing bring your
own journey option when my psychiatrist
said I was treatment resistant. I felt
like a death sentence. I asked if the
psychedelic treatment successes I was
hearing about were worth taking the
risk. Absolutely I was told. Although I
would need to go go it alone because it
was illegal then as it is remains now.
10 years of PTSD was worth the risk to
me and I am grateful for my psychiatrist
had the courage to be so honest with me.
[laughter]
Knowing the medicine to have a
trustworthy safety profile, I was
encouraged to meet the mushroom alone in
the safety and comfort of my own home. I
returned to my psychiatrist in the
following months and finally I was a
treatment re receptive. I spent the next
two years in therapy on the journey to
individuation that became transformative
giving me a new life of wholeness. The
consumption of the medicine is a private
intimate dance into the unknown. My
psychiatrist told me that the brain
hates uncertainty. Facing it alone in
life is far harder than facing it alone
with the mushroom. The lessons learned
are inner direct where no facilitator
can go. There is no reason to expect any
adverse events that threaten life. All
the puffed up training expenses for
therapists who pass those costs on to
patients like me is why the programs are
failing in Oregon and Colorado. Only
rich white patients are able to
participate. Please allow the patient to
choose the bring your own journey
option. I do not want an audience, nor
do I want to pay for unnecessary
upgrades. I am not a commodity for new
business model. I need healing to
survive. Please respect my privacy in
this matter. If other patients too
choose to pay for someone to hold their
hand and they can afford it, so be it.
But old men like me who cannot afford to
pay will be left out in New Mexico. that
would make me a fluke. I believe the
first year of this program should serve
those who cannot pay. That would that
would get notice and set the bar. I
continue my relationship with my psych
psychiatrist who is an avid participant
in this process. Practitioners are
highly valuable and after the
consumption but not so much during it.
So this is this is very heartfelt. This
is exactly what we're trying to
understand as far as this program goes
and I really appreciate um
uh Jim's uh comment here. Um I think we
all understand where he's coming from.
And then uh Gregory Evans uh was saying
uh regarding well participants, I think
we could write this into the uh
recommendation to create a platform for
program development and build in space
for those well hours to be skipped for
reciprocity experiences. doing a ramp up
for legacy practitioners
need to be clear about setting the
education standards versus mitigating
pathways for the ready workforce to be
stood up quickly.
Um, and then Denali was talking about
the DO's recommended CE requirements in
their draft rules right now. Don't
remember the amounts. And then Gregory
said, "Certified clinicians 8 hours, 2
years. Facilitators 20 hours, 2 years.
Practitioners 20 hours, 2 years."
Um, let's see. Uh, New Mexico, uh, this
is by an New Mexico hasn't adopted a
nondirective approach of Colorado,
Oregon. It is a treatment for con
condition X. Uh, Gregory Evans, just to
be clear about, I hear the word being
used, but there's not a medical
prescription in this program. I would
like to invite the committee to re
reinforce this language as the specified
behind this
uh specificity behind this. Okay, Denali
Wilson, thanks Dominic. That's helpful.
Yes, I think we can work in the
registered student piece. I can work on
recommendation language for
incorporating them as one of the two
people required to be present. And uh
Dr. Fatami said, "Thank you all for your
hard work and care. We're so fortunate
to be in New Mexico and what an honor it
is to serve our local community and take
good care and have a lovely weekend."
And uh Jim said, "Thank you." Uh Jim who
stated the the statement of his own
experience in this. So, um after um
going through all of that, uh um we're
ready to take uh who's uh next uh for
comment or um suggestions. Uh is that
Katherine?
>> Yep. Thank you, Brenda, for reading
those. Uh next, Katherine, your mic has
been unmuted.
>> Yes.
>> You may speak.
>> Yeah. Can you hear me?
>> Yes.
>> Can you hear me? Yes. Okay. Awesome. Um,
so a couple things I just wanted to say.
The first is that I do I do want to just
make it I I want us to all be thinking
about the fact that like adding all of
this this training. I think all this
training that we're talking about is is
necessary. It's important, but I I
really struggle whenever I hear people
talking about affordability and then
we're talking about like, you know,
hundreds of hours of training. Like I
don't I I'm not convinced unless there's
subsidies by the state to help out with
training. I'm really struggling to see
how this is going to m you know be more
affordable than the other states because
we're talking about a lot of training
here. Um and [clears throat] so I think
we need to be looking at how can we what
can we do around that? And so one of the
things that came to mind which I I don't
think is much but I just want to throw
it out. I'm also hearing a lot about how
end of life is very specialized and I do
agree that that is the case. It requires
certain expertise that not everybody um
I'd say the majority of licensed
counselors may not have um and social
workers etc. Um, I'm almost wondering if
it needs to be its own track. Like, it
needs to have its own specialty, its own
area of expertise, and its own training
so that we're not adding more training
to everybody's plate, which I'm trying
to think of ways to to make it more
affordable. So, I'm probably being
devil's advocate here by even bringing
this up. I think it can create
complexity, but it might also make
things more simple, um, depending on how
we want to look at it. But I'm just
almost wondering if end of life deserves
its own. Um so anyway, thank you for
listening.
>> Thank you, Katherine. And um uh yes, I
think um I I've been thinking a lot
about this too about uh specialties
because um I think what you brought up
here is having its own track and uh what
would that look like? Uh what would what
would training for um the psilocybin be
in uh that track? And also too um for
addiction too uh addiction is uh uh a
thing that not very many therapists um
are trained in and it's a a special
specialty onto its own. So maybe we
should look at um you know uh these
later on down the road as um specialties
with their own uh types of uh training.
Uh but however, yes, I think you're
absolutely right. um uh the
affordability, the costs, um you know,
how much is all of this going to cost at
this, you know, I don't think we really
have a number yet on what that's going
to be like, but we all think and we all
know that um
uh you know, having a an affordable
training and education
uh format that for everyone would be uh
a wonderful thing to have. Uh but I
we're just not there yet, I think, with
the affordability numbers, but we still
have to have that, you know, in the back
of our brains somewhere. Like, yes, we
would like to have all of the presents
under the Christmas tree. We just can't
do it. But I think what you're saying is
um this is really worth looking at and
maybe the training and education
committee can take a look at that and
see if um we put our heads together and
see if we can um uh come up with
something. Maybe there's something
already out there that uh we don't know
about and that uh that could also be um
an adjunct type of uh education to the
program. I don't know
>> Brenda, there are no hands up at this
moment.
>> Okay. Uh well, let me read this from uh
Jim. Uh trainers feed off of therapists
who pass it on to patients. None of it
is affordable or needed. If a patient
trusts their psychiatrist, that is all
that is needed.
Thank you for that, Jim. Thank you.
And I do want to say this is um a
medical model here that we're looking at
for New Mexico. Um and this is uh one of
the things that um is limiting in in
some respects. However, uh
this is uh the program that we're
working with at this point in time.
Okay. Uh, Desba.
>> Oh, her mic. I think she's having an
issue with her mic.
your mic is unmuted. No.
>> Yeah, I got it. Um,
yeah, thanks for Brenda for pointing
that out again. Oh,
sorry. Um, yeah, thank you for pointing
that out again. Uh and you know it's
it's it's it's one thing to try to hold
on to you know the pristine idealistic
situation where you know a lot of us
have been brought into the medicine um
you know on our own with our own people
whether it's out out in the field in the
mountain at someone's house or however
it is. Um and then it there's also the
track where this is the medical
psilocybin which is being regulated by
the state and again it is finding that
middle ground of you know where at some
point government interference of this
and now there's this kind of moving back
into this space um and at this point
again to reiterate that this is just the
starting point and these are just the
steps you know that we're we're going to
go for forward. Um, I do definitely
appreciate, you know, this idea of C
certifications. My my sister is an RN
and just recently got her flight
certification. So now she is one of
those people who are flying to Roswell
and so forth and transporting NICU
babies back to Albuquerque. Um, and that
was hard to come by. You know, you have
to you have to pass those tests in order
to get the certification for those
things. So they're very very important
and very valuable. Um, so having this
discussion about whether or not we have,
you know, tracks for addiction and then
kind of back to Amy's point, which was a
very long list of things of high
expectations for ourselves. I want to
say that, you know, initially I'm just
kind of thinking like that's a lot of
words. a lot of words and a lot of
expectations and a lot of idealism in
the places of like facilitators,
trainers, cert people people who are
certified to hold space and none of them
none of us as humans I think are able to
uphold to that but it is a great place
to to try to to be at and understand
that. Um and again going back to the
middle ground I'm just thinking about
you know if there is somebody who is you
know uh indigenous or otherwise who has
decided you know the underground who
wants to kind of come into this model
right someone from the underground from
this more idealistic place wants to kind
of come enter into this uh legal
framework you know the barriers that
might be in place to doing so because
what are those transferable skills what
are those transferable ideas of these
ideal ideals that we have of how these
facil facilitators are supposed to be
and I feel like because of the
colonialized capitalistic idea and
expectations of what certification means
that does necess Jim's point and it
means having that language to say you
know I hit all these metrics because
this institution says that I have been
able to hit all these metrics and
ignoring the fact that like in a lot of
places our indigenous and this ancestral
knowledge, these underground pathways in
which we've come to this medicine,
are those words necessarily like being
recognized and is there a pathway
forward for those people who are coming
from the underground into the legal
space? Um, I just kind of wanted to just
point that out is it was something that
was just, you know, jarring to me. Um, I
know that, you know, for for instance,
as a massage therapist, I see a list of
criteria and my immediate trigger is I'm
not doing that. Um, so I just kind of
wanted to point that out. Um, and that
we're trying to find a pathway forward
that yes, there might be barriers. Yes,
there might be but how do we move past
those challenges both in the legal ease,
the words, the certification, the money
but um we are trying to hold that space
for all of these things and we are
trying to going to move forward with the
legalization not legaliz the wrong terms
but you know this legal place where the
government is kind of moving into the
space of like all right uh I can't think
of the word but it's just trying to find
that middle ground from what our
idealized space is And you're right,
nothing essentially is affordable. I
don't know why any of us are paying for
anything. We've come up with this system
that, you know, we're the only living
species that has to pay to live. Cats
don't have to pay for anything. Dogs
don't have to pay for anything. So, yes,
we've got ourselves into these mess, but
this is our way to move out of that
system, I feel. So, anyways, off my soap
box again.
>> Thank you, Despa. Despa, I think that,
you know, you're hitting on a lot of
really uh
um issues that need to be talked about
here. Uh yeah. Uh you know, when we look
at the medical system, you know, it it
it has, you know, its format and uh what
does that mean? Like you really spoke to
me when you said, you know, you know,
when when you're you're massage
therapist and you look at all that stuff
and you go,
yeah, you you know, you are a person of
integrity and honesty and and and and
truth. So it it it's it comes naturally
as as as a provider. Uh
but when but when it's there in black
and white and it's almost kind of like
it's it's dictating to something that
that is uh you know uh set up on a on a
um a pedestal for all of us to reach.
And uh it's
we're we're exactly what right. We're
we're um we're human beings when it
comes comes down to it. And when we have
to do all of these things, how are we
going to uh
uh bring that into uh uh it it's just
that it just feels limiting. I think
this is what I'm trying to get at. Uh
when there's such a high bar here that
uh and hoops that everyone has to jump
through in order to do something that is
um
really so personal
uh with especially if you have a a very
very personal relationship with the
medicine,
you know, uh it it just uh sterilizes
it. I guess that would be the way to say
it. Um
uh but like you said, this is a a
medical program. This is the way it's
set up. But, you know, maybe later on
down the road, we can start to
uh
work out a way to bring these people
into from
wherever they're coming from and have
them
be part of this program. And I think
this is, you know, uh this is just one
step of many things to come. I think as
we
talk about these things in the meetings
and start to um
bridge these gaps and and create
pathways uh that that that are much
needed in this program.
See you Brenda. We do have Lisa. Lisa,
your mic has been unmuted.
Uh great topic and talking about access
would be helpful to understand the ratio
[clears throat] of synchronous and
asynchronous hours for the training.
>> Thank you Lisa. Um we don't have uh in
at least in the proposed rules there is
not a requirement for a particular ratio
for synchronous and non-synchronous or
asynchronous.
>> Are you planning to um create that
requirement or no?
>> Uh that's not in the current proposed
rules.
Um, okay. I will, um, go back to the
chat here again. Um,
let's see. Um, Larry, um, Leman said
that he agrees with Desba that we should
have a legacy pathway.
Um,
uh, Gregory, uh, Evans says, "I feel
like if there were a psychedelic
university with majors and specialized
learning platforms when it comes, uh,
when it when it was coming of age, I may
have chosen that path rather than
managing my own learning. What we are
building here right now is a pathway for
the next generation to learn from the
established knowledge base where it
becomes embraced rather than having to
be lost in the shadows. And Jim Dodson
says, uh, yes, does the bury the medical
model? If it does not respect the
patient, let it fail. And how many like
me have passed on in the last four years
waiting for help that never comes?
And Chris says, "Uh, don't skip me,
Brenda."
>> Okay, [laughter]
>> Chris Chris had a comment saying, "So do
it." Oh, so do I. Rather, sorry. So do
I. [laughter]
>> Brenda, we we do have a hand up. We have
a couple of hands up. Thank you for
reading those.
>> All right,
>> Gregory, your mic has been enabled. You
may unmute yourself.
>> Well, here we are, folks.
Um, in the interest of time, I'm curious
if the committee can come together and
figure out what our deliverable is, what
day we need it delivered, where we are
at with our focus and
what how we can end this meeting
bringing all of this information
together. I think we need to sit with it
a little bit to get to the practicum
hours which is kind of the focus of this
um our immediate need. But uh I just
wondering how we can move forward from
this point and thank you everybody.
>> Thank you Gregory
>> Brenda. We have Despa's hand up.
>> Hi. I just kind of wanted to just to
make a little bit of a clarification.
um you know as as a as being responsible
for the position that I have on the
advisory board you know to me that the
point is to have a conversation and
discussion as a pathway forward as we're
bridging these two or several different
worlds actually into something that we
can support for our people. It may not
we may not provide access for everyone
you know all at once as the gates are
open. it will be a limited number of
people. That's the unfortunate um fact
of this matter where the idealized world
of everything is. My kid wants to burn
everything down. I totally agree. But
before we can do that, when structures
or systems are completely um gone, there
has to either way there has to be a
pathway forward to the idealistic place,
right? So nothing is is just like we'll
burn it all down. It's not about, you
know, completely annihilating all the
systems that are in place. It's about
small steps that we can take and in that
small, it's like the seed of a
cottonwood trace. As I say all the time,
it's like, you know, within that
cottonwood seed are multiple blueprints
for endless amounts of cottonwood seeds.
If we can just find that one small step
towards that pathway to that idealized
state where we're all living in harmony
and bliss, right? That's the right place
to go. And it may be small, but I feel
like we can get there if we are fully
present to the work that we have and and
it is a pathway. Um, but it takes like
small small steps.
>> Thank you, Desbon. Uh, now I see Chris.
>> Yes, Chris. Chris, you're up.
>> She did not forget about you. [snorts]
>> I My comment was so do I was in regards
to uh I agree with Desba that we should
have a legacy pathway. I guess I guess
that wasn't clear, but um
I was
wondering if you know I think Ann's
presentation is a lot closer to where we
need to be than the original regulations
and that but I'm wondering if we
shouldn't maybe take that polish it up a
little bit and um
perhaps have a couple other people um
from outside of our state who are
um
skilled in this field evaluate that and
maybe present on it uh before we make a
decision. And I know that Dominic wants
to get something through in August. But
I also think this is really important
and worth taking our time on. Um we are
moving this program really rapidly and I
think one of the advantage we we had um
was to look at other state access models
and we've completely kind of thrown that
out the door and are reinventing the
wheel all by ourselves. And so I just I
think it's worth the time to have some
uh other outside experts kind of
evaluate what we're doing.
>> You Chris um
>> and I'd be willing to reach out to some
people.
>> Oh that would be wonderful. That would
be a wonderful wonderful thing. Thank
you Chris. I' I'd really appreciate
that. uh and bringing them into uh what
their knowledge base is uh into a
training and education and uh yes have
them contact me um and
we'll um see what uh they what they have
to offer. That'd be wonderful. Thank
you.
All right. Any other comments or
suggestions or
um ideas?
Um, I just wanted to say uh in the chat
uh Jim Dodson says the legacy model has
history while the medical model is built
for profit and itemization.
And uh like I said before, this is the
model that we're working with right now.
Jim and uh we're just trying to get this
um this small step off the ground and uh
yeah I hear this uh quite a lot from a
lot of people. It's it's yes you're uh
your comment is um I think we all
understand that this is this is
something that it's it's a difficult
thing to bridge.
Yes, I see. Uh and Jim also said that uh
Larry said this uh beautiful uh program
team and then Jim said patients are
ignored routinely. We are all used to to
it. Yes. Um uh we understand Jim. Thank
you. Um
>> we do have a couple of hands.
>> Okay. Okay. Uh who's next?
>> Kate. Uh your mic has been enabled.
>> Yeah. Thank you. I I'm [clears throat]
just um I need to get off this call in a
couple minutes and wondering about the
idea of the in a work group in between
these sessions if if that's going to be
something official that you know anybody
who wants to participate can be part of
or if we just keep kind of working
unofficially of those of us who are
involved.
Um Kate, I think um uh
we are um
in in some ways uh working unofficially
uh to gather information to create uh
this working group. Um
uh
this is a good question for Dominic. So
Dominic, I wanted to ask you if I I
wanted to form this group so that um we
could get more support with the
education and training part. Uh it's
unofficial at at this point in time. Do
I need to have an official type of uh
working group?
>> Uh no, Brenda, that would be up to you
to to sort of form that. I mean, just as
a reminder to everyone, Chris alluded to
it a little earlier and we we had
announced it um earlier uh today is that
we are going to be moving forward with a
proposed rule. So, the sooner if there
are specific topics to include in or
suggestions as far as ours, we really
need them sooner rather than later. Now,
we would still be able to adjust some of
that after the, you know, after um the
rule gets published or the proposed rule
rather gets published and even after the
hearing a bit. But um this is a part of
what we've really continuously sort of
been asking is what are the topics
exactly? What needs to be included in?
And um so while it's great to have these
baseline conversations, we really need
to have that specific data. So if that
group wants to get together to get those
specific topics ours that would be
wonderful and then pass that on to us.
>> Thank you Dominic.
>> Okay. Uh next is Lisa,
>> I think. Is it Lisa or Ian?
>> Ian's next actually.
>> Sorry I I was muted myself. Yes, it's
Ian.
>> Hi. [clears throat]
Yes. I just wanted to respond to
um Jim. It is it can happen where
patients are ignored. I'm not going to
deny any patient story. Um but this is
not the forum for that. um the you call
your legislator, have them change the
law, but our job is to enforce and carry
out that legislative duty, but I don't
want to stifle your passion. you are
passionate about the problems that you
have and I want to encourage you to seek
the proper forums and to seek your
legislator and see what can be done to
make things better for patients. Thank
you.
Next is Lisa.
We're at the top of the hour.
this year Mike's been enable
um we have number of students reaching
out to us and asking if they can enroll
in into our Oregon or Colorado
training programs they can transfer that
training later on into New Mexico and as
of now we don't have a clear answer so
we tell them to wait and I would love to
get a little bit more clarification on
this issue.
>> Oh, that's a very good question. Um,
Dominic, what do you think about that
one? Because I think, um, since our our
training in education is, uh, not quite
formed yet, uh,
you know, what would you suggest? uh as
I've been saying since we first started
on the pathway of implementing the
program is until we have the regulations
and that they're clear with regard to
those potential pathways for
reciprocity. Um I could not in good
conscience recommend someone go through
the training. Um but it is in up to them
eventually. Um and um but if you do look
at the draft, there is a pretty good um
outline of what reciprocity may look
like. Um and and again we'll we'll be
doing that hearing really in just I mean
as we were talking towards the end of
August so we're really looking at about
six weeks from now for that public
hearing. So you should um have that
information soon Lisa and for those
students
>> and I think oh
>> I was just [clears throat] going to say
Brenda we since we are at the top of the
hour we do need to set the next meeting
at this point.
>> Okay. Um,
let's see. Uh, DO will be meeting on the
14th. Um, and then Larry has a meeting
on the 14th. Um, uh, we could do, uh,
the 21st, either in the morning or the
afternoon, if that's possible.
>> The 21st currently is open from the
department side.
>> Okay. Um
uh how about uh the morning the 9 to 11?
>> That would work from the department
side.
>> Okay. So our next meeting will be from
uh 9 to 11 on Friday. Uh August 21st.
again. Uh the do has a uh their meeting
on the 14th from uh 1 to 3 and uh Larry
Leman has his um uh his
his meeting from uh 9 to 11. Okay, that
sounds great. Thank you very much. And
thank you all for coming today and
participating. really appreciate every
one of you's comments and suggestions.
Uh this has been a very productive
meeting and uh thank you all for coming
today. Uh hope to see you in the all the
other meetings that are coming down the
pipe here. So, thank you again uh every
one of you for um participating and
thank you uh the board here in Desba,
Chris, uh Dominic, Jorge, uh Ian and uh
everybody, Gregory, Lisa,
uh everyone that's participated and
spoke up. Um and I know there's probably
some people that I've missed, but thank
you very much for coming today. I really
appreciate your input.
And on behalf of the department, I also
would like to thank everybody. It having
this input and the information in these
conversations really helps us to
determine what's going to work best for
the program and of course to continue to
have the conversations and adjust things
as needed as the future arrives. So,
thank you everybody. I hope you all have
a great weekend.